hello everybody thank you for coming to
our second second
special session by geshe michael
thank you for being here we've been
receiving a lot of
feedback from people that want to help
so we're very happy that amongst all
these chaos
there's been a lot of people that offer
to help
thank you geshe michael for taking the
time
thank you
okay thank you seiji and thank you
everyone for coming
uh
i'm gonna do this session i'll i'll talk
for maybe 15 20 minutes
and then uh
we were all going to
uh
you know
everybody was going to write in the chat
uh or speak about something they had
done
to reduce
their own violence and me too you know
so uh you know that was our plan for
today
and uh
so first i'll speak for a few minutes
and then we'll uh i think each one of us
could mention
uh what have i done
to reduce the seeds of violence uh in my
own life
this week or in the last few days and
then
you know let's keep it up
uh
so i was wondering of course uh thinking
about what to say
uh i've had ukrainian friends uh here in
sedona visiting
and uh
yesterday veronica gave a couple hours
of massages
and uh
you know we're trying as much as we can
to help with the refugees and i'm happy
to say that we have raised uh
yesterday fifty thousand dollars
uh from dci and seim
to to assist uh especially uh people in
our groups
uh for refugees coming out of ukraine
and
uh if you if you're in need of help
any kind of help we're we're posting
i'm going to ask seji to post that uh
contact uh information how you can get
help
uh noor ibrahim who uh
was active had was a refugee herself
from syria
seiji's wife
and uh inna
we'll be coordinating
uh
that
how we can distribute help uh from from
here from sedona and from our world
breed groups
so we're trying to target
uh another fifty thousand dollars
and that will make a hundred thousand
dollars
of real
assistance for people who need food
or medical care
or a place to stay so just be in touch
uh with the
contact uh email that we're putting in
the chat
uh
i've been thinking a lot about ukraine
and and i i
talked there a lot
i used to go every year
and
i really enjoy
the country uh i really enjoy
kiev
we we
we gave a lot of talks there a lot of
beautiful talks and the people
are amazing and and very very wonderful
people
and good friends and i
i can remember uh
you know
we did a week in retreats a few times
and uh they said geslar come don't sit
in kiev you know let's go out to the
countryside
and let's see the beauty of of the
ukrainian countryside
and uh
so we we went out to a place called
urban
and i guess those of you who live in
ukraine you you know this place
and it's a beautiful beautiful place and
i remember
uh the drive in the car
uh with my friends igor and anna
driving out
to the earp
and going through the farm areas
of beautiful farms
beautiful green crops
and it was a beautiful beautiful
and i remember uh when we got out of the
car
and we went we reached a beautiful
forest
and
you know i come from arizona and we
have so we don't see the forest very
much and we don't have any trees taller
than geshe michael
and not much and
when i saw the open forest i was wow
this is so
beautiful you know and beautiful small
homes
beautiful
old style ukrainian homes
and it was really
it was really really beautiful
and uh funny thing happened you won't
believe it uh when i got out of the car
and i
there another taxi cab stopped
uh a taxi cab from kiev uh stopped
and uh
this chinese lady got out
you know and um i said oh i know you you
know
you're from hong kong
from china
and she said yeah uh yeah i guess
michael i'm one of your students from
hong kong you know
in china and uh
i said wow you know what are you doing
here you know why did you come to
ukraine
and she said well i've been here once
before
and it's so beautiful
you know it's so so beautiful
uh
the countryside outside of kiev
and uh i i thought i think it was dci
level three or something like that
and she said i would i wanted to come
here
to do this at level three it's
we don't have forest in hong kong like
this you know
and uh so i was wow yeah you're right
this is really beautiful
and i was just really appreciating the
small homes and beautiful
old style homes
and
then we started the
the classes and a big group came from
moscow uh
i don't know if you guys remember maybe
peter and maria remember
but it was a nice
company
uh the the president of the company from
moscow he
he brought i think 17
employees
to the talks and so it was a very
beautiful mixture
of people from kiev and other cities in
ukraine
and a big group from moscow and
everybody was so happy and everybody was
uh
so warm uh to each other and
uh i i had a good time i really had a
good time
and they asked me some tough questions
you know i remember when the question
time came and you know
uh
russian literature is very deep and i
studied it in
in princeton
like dostoyevsky or tostoy and uh
it's very very uh deep
and the first time i went to
saint petersburg
to work on john brady's project at the
national library their
branch
i noticed everybody in the subways and
reading a book you know i couldn't
believe it
you know in in new york subway if you
read a book on the subway
your wallet will disappear very quickly
you know
and
nobody will read a book on the subway
and i was like shocked you know
everybody's
reading books and
you know i checked what's the
title of the books and
they're all very deep books i was i was
surprised you know so it was nice to
have
uh people from moscow st
petersburg asking deep deep questions
and
and i remember a question came up uh in
that at that time in germany
uh
there was a question about uh corruption
you know what to do about corruption
you know how can we help
uh fix corruption in our country and
somebody in asked me in hamburg germany
and uh
so
you know people said geslav what's
what's the seeds uh for corruption and
what do you think about that
and i said uh
and i i had a
inspiration you know i had an idea
how to answer the question
and
i had a microphone if you guys were
there you remember i think peter and
marina you guys igor and
i i took the microphone
and uh
i started to hit the microphone
like this you know
and i'm still talking i said well
how are we gonna talk about the uh
a problem of corruption you know uh how
you know how we gonna talk about
it seems like
it seems like those people who take the
bribe
give them
uh for example we were talking about
highway construction highway
uh construction contract
those people who hit the breath
it seems like they get money back it
seems like it's a good idea to give a
bribe you know in every country you know
um you can get the contract
and uh i was banging on the microphone
and uh everyone was very polite uh
ukrainians people from kiev people from
moscow
everyone was very polite but i can see
they're starting to get irritated
which is my goal actually
and so and uh
i'm banging on
my
finally i remember the
owner of the moscow company he raised
he's very polite
and he raised his hand he said sir uh
please could you stop banging on the
microphone you know it's it's difficult
to understand
what you're saying when when you're
banging on the microphone you know
and i said you know really uh
i want i i want to bang on the
microphone now
but i have to
and then he said why why you have to
bang on the microphone now you know
what's the problem you know
and i said
it's very important
every day
i should bang on the microphone you know
then he's he's like stop stop you're
making me crazy you know
he said uh
why you have to bang up the microphone
every day i said
well
it helps to make the sun come up every
morning
okay when i beg on the microphone
it's a big help
to make the sun come up in the morning
next day
and uh
he said what what are you talking about
you know i said
no really you know i guess you michael's
responsibility special responsibility
every day i have to beg in the
microphone
and then the sun will come up you know
you check tomorrow
and the sun will come up you know
definitely the sun will come out
and he he laughed and he said
quesla are you supershed she are you are
you crazy sumachi
are you crazy you know
and i said i'm not crazy you know
first first this happened
[Music]
and then the sun come up i'm not crazy
he said nah that's crazy you know that's
it came before
you did it the day before it's true
but there's no connection there's no
cause
and effect
connection gestala
not everything happened before
has connection
to what comes later
many things can happen before
and
things happen the next day
but it's not cause and effect it's just
unconnected
like almost like coincidence you know
it's there's no connection
you don't have to bang on the microphone
especially during our talk okay we paid
good money to come to the store you know
it's very irritating for us
then i said well
that's the point i'm trying to make you
see we were discussing
uh corruption
and we were we were had a specific
example from
uh
hamburg that i was talking about
uh somebody
paid a bribe
to get the contract to make a highway
you know
and that guy got very rich okay that guy
became very rich
so this you know people were pushing
this to michael
so how can
a negative thing
make a positive result you know how can
breaking the law
uh create profit
for the guy who's giving the bribe and
that's i said that's why i'm banging on
the microphone you know
there's no connection at all okay
there's no connection at all
okay
yes yes you banged on the microphone
yes the next day the sun came up
yes the guy paid a bribe to somebody in
the government
yes he got the contract for the highway
but they are the same there's no
cause and effect connection it's just
one thing happened before
and the other thing happened later okay
and then they said well what caused the
profit
you know why did the guy make the money
who gave the bribe
and according to
what we understand about seeds
it must be
that he helped somebody before
he shared
what he had freely
what he had with other people this is
the first perfection right giving
so
he must have shared something
in the past
you know you don't get uh
you don't get bananas from a watermelon
seed it's not possible
you know it's funny you know nobody
plants a watermelon seed
and uh expect banana nobody nobody in
the world you know there's some strange
uh
true thing in the whole world
that uh
when you plant a banana you get banana
and when you plant watermelon seed you
get a watermelon
and
when you plant
sharing your money sharing what you have
you get uh money back and you get more
much more why
those seats double
every day okay those seats double every
day small
small gift of money
small help
to people who need help
uh it can create a big big
a big big profit and i'm sorry i was
going to make a mind map but i was too
busy this morning
but in
between uh giving the you know bribe
sorry here's giving the brim
and here's getting the contract right
here's giving the bribe
and here's getting the contract
but what caused the getting the contract
happened earlier
it happened earlier
he this this guy who gave the bribe
earlier in his life he
he gave some help
to someone who needed financial help
and then every day that double double
double
then before the money come back
he gave a bribe but the bribe didn't
cost the money
the gift costs the money okay now
what will happen from the bribe oh that
comes after that okay over here
here's the okay this is time right
over here uh
we will get the result hey masha why you
not got your fingers up to translate hey
bertha
hey you romanian
okay yeah yeah yeah you got it it's
difficult
it looks a little funny
yeah this one is
you got that
later you will get trouble
this will be the result later
uh
from
from doing the brim okay so why are we
talking about that today
we have serious problems to talk about
you know
but but i'm i i'm thinking about that
talk
because i gave it an open
uh with the chinese lady there
and the guys from moscow and and all the
people from kiev and
harkov and other
cities
and
you know the airplane is now uh
destroyed
the the forest the the houses uh
much of it is destroyed in in the last
few days
and so i'm thinking about it you know
i'm thinking a lot about it
and i'm thinking uh
you know
how can we help this problem how can we
all
help this problem what can we do you
know
and i keep coming back to the pen okay
if you heard me teach the pen before
don't forget you have to hear three
thousand times okay
so
i know uh octavian i know it's two
thousand five hundred okay i know you
didn't finish three thousand
okay
so
so yeah
uh the pen story sounds funny
the pen story doesn't seem very
important today
but
there's one important thing about the
pen story
is it's true
it's 100
true
okay and and nobody i've been teaching
the pen almost
40 years
nobody
in the world
told me it's not true except
one
stupid american guy from florida but we
don't have to worry about stupid
american guy from florida
okay
everybody agree
uh the pen story is
is true okay what
uh when you show this to human
they see pen
when you show this to a dog
they see
chew toy okay
and without debate
without question okay if you're not from
florida
uh
this pin
must be coming this way no sorry this
way okay this pin this thing
octavian got it right this like just do
it octavian's thing
yeah
it's the pen is coming from you okay
obviously
obviously if the dog sees chewtoy
if the human sees pen
then
the same pieces the same black the same
white
the same cylinder
okay
if if the dogs see one thing
and if the humans see a different thing
it's not just the dci story it's not
just the gesture michael story
it's the truth of the whole world you
see
if the
pen
is coming from you
then everything is coming from you how
much
how many things in the world
how many events how many problems how
many joys
are coming from you
okay 100
no exceptions okay we in this week i'm
just like you uh we're all the same
i'm like god
i didn't do any big uh bad things
recently
to see this terrible terrible
suffering i i didn't do any bad things
like that
we're all the same we're all thinking
the same thing god i
i was trying pretty good you know i i
was trying to make good seeds
uh for for years
and why i have to see this thing you
know what's what's the
what's the purpose i don't understand
you know what
what did i do
and and if you understand the pin
you have to say it comes from me you
have to say
it comes from me
if this small pin
come from you
then
everything comes from you 100
not 50
not 60 percent
everything comes from me every single
thing
comes from me and then we have to go to
the kitchen okay
and i was in the kitchen uh this morning
having coffee okay
my wife came in the kitchen she said
i'll make you some
breakfast before you get on the ukraine
car you know and i'm like yeah let's try
fast
actually uh maria i got half the
breakfast
i have to finish the other half later
uh
then we always talk about
this story
about the husband in the kitchen right
and
we're talking about it for 10 years or
something you know
like you go
i don't know this morning it didn't
happen but if i wake up in the morning
and i go in the kitchen
and
my wife i i'm still sleepy right and uh
i i i'm not talking yet get your
michael's mouth
you guys think it never stops but in the
morning
it it takes a while like an older engine
car
it has to warm up you know so i'm like
uh
and uh actually my wife told me please
don't say uh
in the morning you know you sound like
an old car
and
then suppose uh suddenly veronica said
to me you're so stupid you know you're
so stupid
suppose she says that suddenly to me
then if i understand the pen
you know
then i i must must must must
must
remember
in the difficult time
okay in the difficult time
i must remember
it's coming from me it's coming from me
it's coming from me
and then i will not give the wrong
reaction you see
if i if veronica say
michael don't make this
in the morning you know just
keep your mouth shut until you give your
ukraine talk
and
then i say
and she said that's so stupid you know
then uh
you know she's gonna say
then i'm gonna think
oh
she criticized me you know
i
i don't know why she must be in a bad
mood you know and then natural natural
natural human reaction natural natural
natural
human reaction i want to
fight back you know i want to fight back
i want to say i'm not stupid you're
stupid you know
and then uh
geshe michael will have a
zoom call
with all his friends uh
how should i fight back to my wife you
know should i
yell at her
maybe i can throw a
coffee cup
or maybe i can stamp my feet
you know or maybe i can give her we call
silent
treatment right
it's like i'm i'm angry but i'm not
gonna talk to you
you know so
which choice you know i call my friends
together i call john brady
you know hey john
veronica call me stupid this morning
which which is the
reaction
should i yell at her
should i call her stupid you know should
i
should
i you know should i give her silent
angry silent treatment and john is like
this on the zoom call
[Music]
you know if i call john brady
i say
this morning in the kitchen
veronica call me stupid you know john
what should i do should i say she's
stupid
you know should i be silent and angry
you know should i should i hurt her a
lot or should i hurt her a little should
i hurt her small way or should i hurt
her big way and john brady you know him
all the time he's like based on the
microphone guess you are don't forget
airplane
don't forget i was there in ipad
don't forget to talk you gave to the
moscow guys
don't forget to talk you'll get to the
kiev guys
there's no connection
between what you do
at that moment
and what she respond okay there's no
connection at all zero zero
do violence do big violence do small
violence
do quiet violence
uh
do
do very intelligent violence
just like
uh
some kind of sarcasm
you know and it's all useless
it
from the big violence
to the little violence
it's all the same you are hitting the
microphone
and you're you're thinking the sun is
going to come up
[Music]
it's not connection there's no
connection okay
if i say veronica you're stupid
and she stops calling me veronica
it's not because i said you're stupid
it's not because i did violence back to
her
if the violence stopped
because i did violence
it's like paying the bribe for the
contract if there's no connection
there's no connection okay any kind of
violence i do
in response
even small violence
even mental hatred violence
okay oh gesh la i'm i'm i'm studying
with you for many years
i understand i shouldn't say bad things
i understand i shouldn't shoot people i
understand
i understand i shouldn't answer that way
but in my heart
i'm answering with hatred
i'm i'm calling those people you are bad
people
you don't understand anything you know
you are
you are stupid violent people you know
uh in my heart
i am answering i i understand
i shouldn't hurt people with my hands
or my mouth
but in my heart
i really hate what what these people are
doing and i hate these people
and i'm sorry it's just how i feel you
know but
but that's the worst thing you know
that's of all the
seeds this is the worst thing okay so of
of course
nobody who who learned the pen of course
we we cannot answer with violence cannot
uh physical and we cannot answer with uh
even talking violent talks
but uh
the deepest seeds are planted by
thinking
that the heaviest seeds are planted by
uh
so that's oh man that's a difficult
question you want me to
to not hate people who are hurting my
family my country you you want me not to
hate them
that's too much you know i can't do that
you know i can
i can be non-violent but but not to hate
them is is too much you know
but you see that plant's a seed
that makes the seed
that creates the violence you see the
violence is coming the pen is true
the kitchen the two has been in the
kitchen is true okay
and all this violence coming from uh
mostly from my heart how i feel towards
other people and i i have to
stop being around the microphone okay it
doesn't help
it hurts everybody okay it's irritating
in the room
so
so the main job we all have
and the way we can help
of course we have to help
the refugees and we are all helping
yesterday
the sedona people gave 50
i believe uh in the next two days we
will have another 50 000
for medical care
uh food a shelter
of of people who need it okay of course
of course we have to do that
but at the same time
we have to understand
that the main solution is to stop
violence in our heart right
any kind of hatred
any kind of ah you are so stupid you
know like that
it's it's the same in the kitchen
and the same for a whole country it's
the same international
relationship
and relationship with your wife
at breakfast
the principles are the same everything
comes from us everything comes from us
okay
all right so how we can help
in oh geshlar give me practical way
don't talk about spiritual way give me
practical weight no
the spiritual way is the practical way
okay the spiritual way is the practical
way
so what do you want me to do what should
i do
let's look
if we have any seeds inside of us
of of violence okay and and so this is
kind of a confession time for the next
uh we have about
i don't know almost half an hour it's
kind of a
sojourn sojourn means group
confession of our bad seeds you know
uh talking
openly
about our bad seeds okay and and let's
do together okay and and i will start
okay so i was checking uh
am i doing any small violence in my life
and and i am sometimes i'm doing small
things
uh to hurt my family members and and i
they are not big okay uh gesla doesn't
shoot the gun
to his family members or geshla doesn't
hit them
but there are small
things they want from me
there are small things they ask me to do
and and i and i didn't do it i i could
have done it that's the idea
i wasn't too busy
and uh i didn't care enough okay
it wasn't i was too busy
it's that i didn't
i didn't care enough
to
to stop doing the thing that hurt them
that they don't like you know
so uh that's my
uh
small seeds of violence
oh geshla you didn't create
international war
by
by disappointing your family members and
and i say yes i believe i did
for for me
the war came from that i believe so
uh and what i can do what i commit to do
is to stop making that see so guess yes
michael
who's doing small violence at home
small subtle violence i i will uh
i make promise to all my brothers and
sisters on this call
from all countries
i will try to stop that
for five more days and then let's meet
again okay so if you want to
so five more days i i will uh
i will try to stop this small violence
okay seiji
uh
let's go to other people and and i'm
just gonna relax and not talk so much
and
i'm interested
how you guys are gonna stop your small
violence and then let's get together
again next week okay
do you want us to share what people have
wrote on the chat or people just to open
their mic
up to you seiji i i what i don't want
is any kind of criticism of any country
or criticism of any government uh we are
we are criticizing ourselves
uh we are not criticizing uh other
people other countries so um let's make
this agreement
uh original things are in the chat
better okay okay
so thank you ellie van der pass for
being the first one to share
she mentioned us something similar like
you said to stop violence
we have a group of women who meet every
two weeks
and this morning we were talking about
what what we have been doing to stop
violence in our lives
helping each other
rejoice and be happy when we have been
able to
okay cool
hey sanji i say we let people talk but
but i want to make an agreement
if anyone starts to criticize another
person
or if anyone starts to criticize another
country
uh i'm asking seji to cut them
to cut that one okay
all right
okay here we go
let's try
okay
and uh sanji can you make a time limit
of uh three minutes or something okay
sure
and we just cut we just cut you off
thank you
the next person that wrote on the chat
is dorte dorte would you be able to open
your mic and tell us about this
yeah
yes i can
we discussed on the way to our
how we
uh
small ways may be violent to our members
how we behave bossy
and put
not to do that
simply by
the last entering the meeting room or
calling on
i have important news and not looking
for whether they are working
contemplated
and we found
thought we could try to
stop that
and to think about
when we do these things and remember it
and train it
cool
okay cool thank you
thank you seji you have another person
thank you very much dota
yes we have connie o'brien who
wants to tell us her
sojourn confession
okay so my story is going to a green
juice bar where they serve very
peaceful food nonviolent food
you get some food there and i'm standing
in line and somebody but right in front
of me
it went really hot i was just like oh
boy what are you doing
i could feel the heat inside and i'm
thinking to the lady who took his money
i'm not going to give you a tip
and i thought about the pen of course
and it was like oh connie you better not
do this so i did exactly as i always did
uh which is to give a good tip and think
about what i've done in the past
to create this what i've taken where
i've crossed the line
and taken something from somebody else
and that was so helpful it just passed
immediately so thank you guys
cool by the way connie and other guys
uh
i grandpa has learned this method to
talk
that after every sentence i take a deep
breath
and then octavian doesn't have a
breakdown
trying to translate too fast and bertha
okay here we go who's up next cj
next we have ella
hello
my first thought
when i heard gestula speak last week
was i'm good
why do i see world in my work war in my
world
because i believe in the seeds
so i had to watch myself and i've been
watching myself
and
many times a day
i get irritated
at little things
the website doesn't load fast enough
my customers
they don't listen
and so i've been watching
and being
shocked at myself but stopping
and rejoicing that i caught myself
so that's what i promised to do
this week
yay thank you
thank you
okay stevie who's up
can you show the video cg of people no
i don't know
i think i am the next one hello it's
anna
okay
it was me next
yeah please go for it
okay thank you so after the call we had
last week with yogisha michael i
realized that i was swearing a lot in my
mind
i'm not being violent with people with
my words but what's going on in my head
yeah
so um
i first that was the first step to
realize it and uh now i'm trying to be
more calm
and
i did a lot of tongue glenn
on the violence from the past
so i am planting mental seeds for
deactivating the mental seeds of
violence
thank you
seiji is there a way to uh spotlight the
person who's talking uh yes brian would
you be able to help us with that
sure thanks
okay
we have bob would you be able to open
your mic and tell us
what you said in the chat please
bob cerino
all right
if not i can go um
hey brian brian can you spot can you uh
oh i'm sorry i don't have a camera with
me right now uh you just didn't put your
clothes on today i know
okay
i i found that in the last couple weeks
i have been enjoying
tv and movies
that have war in them
and i can't believe
how much i enjoyed watching these things
and i would look forward to it and i saw
it as fun
and that was really sad for me
uh to realize that i was taking pleasure
in that
so um
one of my favorite tv shows which is
pretty violent
um
just released a new season and i've
committed to
not watch it until
this entire conflict
finishes and then at that point
i may not have the desire at all anyway
anymore
great that's perfect that's perfect yeah
yeah thank you bob
seiji you you want to try
we have
oh hey spotlight yourself spotlight
yourself
uh
i have personally a lot of um
[Music]
impatience and anger so
what i've been trying to do is two
things one is
you taught us in in dci impossible anger
i like to call macho dude which is
trying to hold off
just a few seconds before getting angry
and so that we plant seeds to be able to
increase it a lot later so that's what
i've been trying to do when i get a
uh
irritating
or
whatever
so
that has been what i've been trying to
do
perfect perfect next we have uh alison
okay allison
can you spotlight her alison jo she said
she doesn't have a camera either ah she
didn't comb her hair that's the thing
sorry
i tried to watch for my mouth which
means my verbal speech
in the past few days even today in the
morning
and
and i try to stop even the small try to
do i stop the small violence because
sometimes when i see something which is
not done correctly or not dying the
right way for example by
my partner or
my and then i would just somehow just
point it out and then i was thinking
maybe i i would try to do it in a more
skillful and sweet way so actually this
morning i realized that i noticed
something that
um
that
that my partner promised me to do that
he will help me do it but i noticed he
didn't do it and then i was thinking
okay i'll represent you i want to ask
him why you didn't do that and then and
then and i decided
i i just keep silent i said okay i must
forgot before so and then i instead i
decided to tell him
thank you for doing everything for for
me so instead just
ask him why you didn't do nothing for me
by instead i thank him for thank you for
doing other things for me yeah
cool nice
thank you
who's next handsome cg
i think we had uh someone called kirsten
schmidt would you be able to please on
uh
open your mic and share with us
and can you spotlight her camera
maybe we jump to another one i'm
promoting i see we have vimeola here
would you be able to jump in
hi
hi everybody
so
i've been working um lately on violence
against my own self and
in meditation actually in the last three
days i went back to the lions dance and
i went back to my past lives
and so i was sending love and compassion
like this universal love to my past
lives
and
and feeling and i was actually feeling
like i was healing my past
and then i would come back and
then i would send it out and send this
love and compassion to
the world and in in the present moment
and what is happening now in the world
and since there's no past and there's no
future and there's just this present
moment
i really was feeling this this feeling
of love and compassion to the whole
world and i think it's really been
helping me a lot
cool
cool thank you thank you vimelan
i please thank dekey for the time but i
had some good samples today
okay cg who's next uh we have olaf
fitzgerald who wanted to who shared
something in the chat hi
hi hi thank you
um i had the realization
is one of my contemplation meditation
and um
and it began with this reflection on the
conflict between ukraine because
originally from ukraine uh from gorod
from city nicolai
south of ukraine and um
and this conflict and as a result
um
i
of my reflex i find out is a my
cleaning to my
and it starts
out so innocuous
like i take care of my body of my house
i
it's my car it's my food
it's my money and it's gone on and on
and on forever
and every day i cling to my
and this small mental imprint
of my
turns in a huge
of your my conflict of state
and um
and obviously is nothing really mine and
um our body is what we have
temporarily
and a house and um
and there is uh
millions and millions of years this land
was existed with it for me
and it will exist after me
and so it is stupid to fight for land
yeah and um and i just thought okay what
practice i can do
to start change that
and
my thoughts is
let's change our
thinking of my
to feeling of gratitude
cool that's very beautiful i think it's
very helpful yeah thank you
very beautiful stagey
who's next we have mr timothy lowenthal
thank you
so i've been thinking a lot about
um
like the different levels of of reality
when we talk about evidence reality and
hidden reality
and i've been thinking about that when i
talk to people
what's obvious for me
that might be hidden for them
and you know then what's obvious for
them that might be hidden for me
and i realize in a lot of the
conversations i've been having of how
much i'm assuming
is going on for people there's the story
i create about them who they are what
their motivations are
why they do what they do
and realizing that i don't ask enough
questions and so i'm
finding myself
catching myself judging people about who
they are
without really knowing what's hidden for
like what's what am i not seeing about
them
so
my practice has been about
in removing that that's attempting to
remove the stories i create about other
people because i really think most
conflict
comes from that where we assume what's
going on without asking enough questions
so that's been my practice um
since last week so thank you again for
for inspiring them
cool and thank you for helping so much
uh
with the fundraising and uh you're
tirelessly helping to raise funds for
all the good things and thank you very
much for that yeah thank you
you have another person
yeah yes we have kadrin
hi karden
hakari
this is uh
high tech
grandpa's high tech
okay thank you very much for reminding
me
um this time i found
uh
that i do
what i want to do
my way
and i want others to do it my way and
i
got joy
when others
be scared of me
when
i see something they do in a wrong way
wrong way i
say no
do it my way
and i got
a little bit angry and i
make them do it my way
uh it's like
my nephew is watching uh tv or computer
games
and
i want him to stop he is doing it for
three hours
in a row
and i say just stop it
he said no five minutes about five ten
minutes more i said no
stop it
go do your homework
and
it's violence
yesterday i thought how can i do it in a
different way how can i do
in a nice way how can
i make a commitment with them to the
children to
to find a way to do it without violence
and it was my
justice insight
about my way of
bringing violence in this world and
this is the way how i see this war
because somebody wants
something
this way
yeah
thank you very much
and and thank you for your constant hard
work you're always working so hard
especially translating and
i don't know how your head didn't blow
up yet
but uh thank you for that and uh thank
you for arena she's been really
wonderful uh here helping
uh
seiji
you haven't had it
okay yes we have uh tracy mckenzie
from where new brunswick canada
oh what's that a boot
okay here's a grandpa
high-tech reminder
okay
um i've been very aware
of um resistance and the resistance is
trying to see things the right way so
i've been really going deep to analyze
my mind my thoughts and how i'm
constantly in and out of trying to
see things the right way
so i feel that there's clarity coming
from how often i'm judging and i thought
i wasn't judging and i'm really judging
and i'm i'm also thinking i see things
one way oh i know this and one moment
later i don't and and then i'm thinking
do they know do i know so i feel like
there's a war in my mind
slowly
[Music]
so yeah
i'm really the analyzing not just when
i'm meditating
but from the moment i get out of bed
my whole day tonight
deep level of awareness
and every time i'm
judging i feel
a stop
i pause
i smile
inwards to myself and i feel like my
heart has radiating lights and i just
send it out to my family my community
my country all over the world and i'm
just hopeful that i can play a role to
feel like i'm helping in some way
thank you very much very beautiful tracy
uh seiji i think we have time for one
more person huh and uh then we'll we'll
continue next week let's do every week
for a while okay we'll try every week
okay
we have uh lauda laura bordera not sure
from where
you're from spain from barcelona
hi
hi laura hi
uh it's less the same as tracy said
my i'm focused on the yeah okay slowly
i'm focused on the little violence
against my family
mainly
especially to my teenage or girl
uh sometimes i kill
even
i can
stay
quiet
after she yells at me
but there's violence in my head mostly
and i think the only way to stop it is
remember sits
remember she comes from me
that's
really the only thing that
uh stopped the violence takes a while
but is the only way
cool and
just the only thing is i still
judging myself for this for not remember
seats
and i realize it's a big
source of violence again
so i'm asking also to be
have mercy with myself
nice thank you
thank you very much so we're gonna stop
there today but i'd like to add two more
things
uh first thing
if anyone needs help
in europe any country doesn't matter
if you need food
if you need a place to stay
you need
financial help you need money to travel
you just want to talk to somebody
then
here's the information link
seiji has put it in the chat
we do have money
uh we have a fundraise successfully
uh if you need help
don't be shy okay and don't be proud if
you know
if we need
help we're gonna contact you
so it's all one family we are all big
family
and anyone who needs help uh just
contact
uh those uh
those different addresses
in the chat secondly and most
importantly
please think about banging on the
microphone
[Music]
think about that story from earpin
and let's not
don't waste time
doing anything
that doesn't help okay don't waste your
time
uh
talking bad about other countries
uh you know getting angry doing violence
even thinking someone else is stupid or
something like that
this is this is banging on the
microphone
it's not going to help the situation it
cannot it cannot help
no kind of negativity
can help this situation each one of us
has to
find
the small
violence we are doing
stop barking
okay all right and uh we're gonna meet
again let's meet every week
uh for this time this difficult time and
let's help each other emotionally and uh
with material help okay
so seiji do you have a
idea for next week time or anything like
that or should we announce it later
yeah i think we should announce it later
and okay
for those of you
on youtube
uh please uh
make sure that you write if you need any
help
please write us at this email info at
diamondcarterinstitute.com
we will also share
uh
a couple of
files that we uh
that of questionnaires that tim made but
if in the meantime if you need to
contact someone fast please write us
here
info at
diamondcutterinstitute.com institute is
spelled incorrectly
there's a there's a missing tee
oops
yeah
i do that all the time okay okay
okay
institute yeah thank you too
all right
all right thank you guys thank you
stevie for for working so hard thank you
tim for working so hard and we'll see
you guys in about five days let's do
every five days
okay and let us know if you need any
kind of help okay and watch watch for
small seats of violence
and let's let's all confess i i will
have some new confession for next time
okay all right thank you guys
we love you